(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-16T00:09:54.099022",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
右に進めば...
If I go right...
左の道なら...
If it's the left path...
正解は？
What's the correct answer?
チャンスか
Is it a chance?
リスクが小さい？
Is the risk smaller?
やっぱり右？
Right after all?
後悔したくない...
I don't want to regret...
ビターチョコデコレーション / 作詞・作曲: syudou
[Bitter Chocolate Decoration / Lyrics & Composition: syudou]
人を過度に信じないように
In order to not trust people excessively,
愛さないように 期待しないように
not to love, and not to expect anything,
かと言って角が立たないように
yet at the same time, not to cause friction,
気取らぬように 目立たぬように
not to be pretentious, and to stay out of the spotlight.
誰一人傷つけぬように
In order to not hurt a single soul,
虐めぬように 殺さぬように
not to bully, and not to kill,
かと言って偽善がバレないように
yet at the same time, not to let my hypocrisy show,
威張らないように
and not to act superior.
軽いジョークやリップサービスも忘れぬように
In order to not forget light jokes or lip service,
どんな時も笑って愛嬌振りまくように
to always smile and show charm at any moment.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter chocolate decoration...
とかく言わずに たんと召し上がれ
don't say this or that, just eat it up.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter chocolate decoration...
食わず嫌いはちゃんと直さなきゃ
you must fix your habit of hating foods before trying them.
頭空っぽその後に残る
If what remains after emptying your head
心が本物なら
is a genuine heart...
きっと君だって同じ事
I'm sure you must feel the same way.
ところで一つ伺いますが
By the way, there's just one thing I'd like to ask...
やっぱいいや
Never mind.
無駄に自我を晒さぬように
So as not to expose your ego needlessly,
話さぬように
so as not to speak,
分からぬように
so as not to be understood.
でも閉ざした口は閉ざさぬように
But make sure you don't close your closed mouth,
笑うよりは笑われるように
to be laughed at rather than to laugh.
人をちゃんと敬うように
Make sure you respect people properly,
崇めるように
to revere them,
讃えるように
to praise them.
でも決して嫌味にならないように
But make sure you never sound sarcastic,
ふざけないように
make sure you don't mess around.
集団参加の終身刑
A life sentence of participating in society,
またへーこらへーこら言っちゃって
bowing and scraping once again.
「あれっ、前髪ちょーつえーさいきょーじゃん！」
"Oh, your bangs look absolutely amazing!"
とかどーでもいーのに言っちゃって
Saying things like that even though you don't care,
毎朝毎晩もう限界
every morning and night is already the limit.
宗教的社会の集団リンチ
The mass lynching of a religious society,
でも決して発狂しないように
but make sure you never go mad.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter Choco Decoration.
時に孤独な愛は君を汚す
Sometimes, lonely love will stain you.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter Choco Decoration.
立つ鳥の後きっと糞のアート
A departing bird surely leaves behind an art of feces.
初めはあんな大層な大言壮語を並べたが
At first, you boasted such grand words,
嫌よ嫌よも好きの内
but saying no often means yes.
「いやはやしかし今日が初めてで
"My, my, but to think today is the first time...
こんなとはね 君センスあるよ」
To be like this... you've got good taste."
恋い慕う季節に
In the season of yearning love,
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter Choco Decoration.
恋い慕う季節に ビターチョコデコレーション
In the season of yearning love, Bitter Choco Decoration.
恋い慕う気持ちで ビターチョコデコレーション
With a yearning feeling of love, Bitter Choco Decoration.
F.U.C.K.Y.O.U
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter Choco Decoration,
皆が望む理想に憧れて
longing for the ideal that everyone wishes for.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter Choco Decoration,
個性や自我は全部焼き払い
burning down all individuality and ego.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter Choco Decoration,
欲やエゴは殺して土に埋め
killing off desire and ego, burying them in the dirt.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter Choco Decoration,
僕は大人にやっと成ったよママ
Mother, I've finally become an adult.
明日もきっとこの先も
Tomorrow as well, and surely from here on too,
地獄は続くどこまでも
hell will continue on forever.
だからどうか今だけは
So please, if only for now,
子供の頃の気持ちのままで
with the feelings of a child...
一生忘れてやってこうぜ
Let's forget about it for the rest of our lives!
ああ思い出した
Ah, I remembered.
あの時のクソ真面目な僕
The extremely serious me from back then...
やっぱいいや
Never mind.
あ...
Ah...
サイコロ...
The dice...
5が出た
I got a five.
ん？
Hmm?
何これ？
What's this?
椅子？
A chair?
One, two, one...
アップダウンは世の常
Up and down is the way of the world.
クズ引いたって動じない
I won't be shaken even if I draw garbage.
肝心なのは strong な mind
What's important is a strong mind.
出し抜いて survive
Outsmart them and survive.
行きつく先は heaven or hell
The destination we'll reach is heaven or hell.
この世界のルール
The rule of this world is...
たった一つ 勝者こそが正義
only one: the winner is justice.
女は度胸
A woman needs courage.
焦れさせるのアイツを
To make him feel impatient,
やれることなんだってやる
I'll do whatever it takes.
あたしは賭け狂いのクイーン
I am the gambling-obsessed queen.
お見通しそれ you doubt me
I can see right through it, you doubt me?
読み切ってレッツ showdown
Reading you completely, let's showdown.
deal with the devil
見透かして
See right through it,
あたしのものにする
and make it mine,
あなたの髪の一本まで全部
down to every single strand of your hair.
a million dollars I'd say raise
震えてるわよ坊や
You're trembling, little boy.
降ろさせはしないわ
I won't let you fold.
deal with the devil
uhhhh nn 興奮
Mmm, excitement...
たまらないわスリル
This thrill is irresistible.
誰にも触らせないこの money
I won't let anyone touch this money.
仕掛けて
I'll use them in a trap
罠に嵌めるわ
to catch you.
油断誘うのよ
I'll lure your carelessness.
思考を止めたら ジ・エンド
If you stop thinking, that would be the end.
何も知らないような表情で
With a face that says I don't know a thing...
堕とすわ あなたを<
I'll bring you down.
虚勢でしょ それ you doubt me
You're bluffing, aren't you? You doubt me.
読み切って レッツ showdown
Reading all the signs, let's have a showdown.
deal with the devil
見逃さない
I won't miss it.
どんな小さなズルだって
No matter how small the cheat is,
あたしの目はごまかされないわ
you can't fool my eyes.
a million dollars i'd say raise
勝った相手は骨まで愛しつくしてあげる
I love the ones I conquer all the way down to their bones.
狙った獲物は逃がさない
I won't lose sight of my prey.
唇濡らして頂くわ my babe
I'll be wetting my lips before I taste you, my babe.
ダイヤのジャックで手か揃うわ
With the jack of diamonds, my hand will be complete.
笑みを殺し待つだけ
I just have to hide my smile and wait.
あたしのポーカーフェイスは it's perfect
My poker face? It's perfect.
一分の隙も見せたりしないわ
I won't show even a single opening.
視線感じてるわ
I can feel your gaze.
お望みは最後まで
If you want it all, until the very end...
見てばかりいないで
don't just keep watching me,
あたしとしていかない？
won't you play with me instead?
負けるのが怖い？ you're easy game
Are you afraid to lose? This is an easy game.
読み切って レッツ showdown
Reading all the signs, let's have a showdown.
deal with the devil
見透かして
I'll see right through you
あたしのものにする
and make you all mine,
あなたの髪の一本まで全部
down to the very last hair on your head.
a million dollars i'd say raise
震えてるわよ 坊や
You're trembling, my boy.
とことんまで行くわ
We're gonna take it all the way.
deal with the devil
uhhhh nn 興奮
brings endless excitement...
たまらないわ スリル
I can't get enough of this thrill.
誰にも触らせない この money
I won't let anyone touch this money.
a million dollars i'd say raise
さあ com'on 覚悟キメて
So come on and make up your mind,
ハイになるまで打って
keep hitting until we're high.
欲しがるようじゃね まだ ベイビー
Only ever wishing means you're still a baby.
誰にも負けない
I won't lose to anyone.
感じさせて love me honey
So make me feel like no one else can: love me, honey.
ほら、椅子持ってかれちゃった
Look, they took my chair away.
あぁ、もうちょっと座らせて欲しかったー
Ah, I wanted to sit a bit longer.
はいみんなー！見えてるー？聞こえてるー？
Hi everyone! Can you see me? Can you hear me?
ホロライブ所属の癒やし系ハーフエルフ、アキロゼことアキ・ローゼンタールです！
I'm the healing half-elf from Hololive, Aki Rosenthal, also known as Akirose!
ハローハローハロー！アローナー！
Hello, hello, hello! Alona!
はぁー！えー、今回の...
Whew! Now, for this...
アキロゼ生誕祭2026へようこそ！
Welcome to the Akirose Birthday Live 2026!
はぁ、早速ね、なんか色々行われていたんですが、一体今回のライブはどうなっちゃうのか？
Whew... Things already got started, but what's going to happen in this live show?
ぜひ最後まで必見！お見逃しなくお願いします！
Be sure to watch until the very end! Please don't miss it!
今回のライブのハッシュタグは、「アキロゼ生誕祭2026」
The hashtag for this live is 'Akirose Birthday Live 2026'...
こちらをつけてXにたくさんポストしてね！
Please post a lot on X with this hashtag!
もちろん、可愛い...
Of course, a cute...
スクショ...
screenshot...
えー、も、たくさん撮って、
please take lots of screenshots,
合わせて投稿してください！ライブが終わった後、アキロゼ見に行きます！
and post them as well! I'll go check them out after the live is over!
見てね！あ、チャンネル登録もよろしくね！
Take a look! Oh, and please subscribe to my channel too!
オッケー？オッケー？オッケー？オッケー？
Okay? Okay? Okay? Okay?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
なんだ？何？何？何？
What's this? What, what, what?
え？
Eh?
うーん、っていうか、ここどこなんだろう？
Hmm, by the way, where is this place?
おっ？あんなところにルーレットがある！
Oh? There's a roulette over there!
え、回るのかな？
Eh, does it spin?
おっ、えっ、回っ...
Oh, eh, it's spi...
回った！えー、すごい！おー、回った！
It spun! Wow, amazing! Oh, it spun!
さあ、えー、何が出るんだろう？
Now, what will it be?
あ、え、あ、え？
Ah, eh, ah, eh?
な、何？何？どうなっちゃうの？
W-What? What? What's going to happen?
え？あ...
Eh? Ah...
ピース？お？
Peace? Oh?
ん？なんだ？
Hmm? What is it?
A happy...
A lucky...
Be happy...
UNDEAD
目を逸らした過去も
Even the past we turned away from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future,
カウンセリング やれやれ
it's counseling, my oh my.
古今東西 ピースピース
All times and places, peace peace!
A happy...
A lucky...
Be happy...
UNDEAD
ね、ね、ね、何とか通して
Hey, hey, hey, let me through somehow.
戦っているようなそんな気がするの
I feel like I'm fighting somehow...
この自分
this self of mine.
あぁ 独り死んでると
Ah, when I'm dying alone,
目に見えるデッドオアアライブ対決
a visible dead-or-alive showdown.
痛いけで 痛い痛い 記憶の奥 残念
It hurts, painful, painful deep in memory, too bad.
もういないのに あれ？そっちがアイロニー
Even though they're gone... Huh? That's irony.
急かされているのは今の自分
The one being rushed is my current self.
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, an indelible label.
家業コンプレックス 取り憑かれているみたい
Like being haunted by a family complex,
巻き添い喰らったまま まだ離れない
dragged into it, still unable to escape...
在りし日の自分 UNDEAD
my former self, UNDEAD!
信じられない お前と前の連鎖
Unbelievable chain of you and the past.
生きているかと問う 終わり続ける方
Asking if I'm alive, the one that keeps ending.
そっと裏に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't just settle for the shadows and be satisfied.
幸せになろうとしちゃいけないなんて 嘘だ
It's a lie to say we shouldn't try to be happy.
この世、この世は 奇々怪界ファンタジー
This world, this world is a bizarre fantasy!
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Will a demon or a snake appear next?
会って会ってやっと 始まる物語
Meeting at last, the story finally begins.
先手勝ち逃げなのか ここんとうざいピースピース
Is it a quick win? Peace peace all over!
Ah, the future
Can't change the past
But the future
Love for the future
なんだかどうして
Somehow, some way,
未来になんとかなるの<
it'll work out in the future.
よう、ラッキーして
Yo, get lucky!
もう十分生きてる 意志鑑定ブレて食傷
I've lived enough, resolve wavering and fed up.
宿敵だなんて 気心の気配もない 残念
A lifelong rival, yet no trace of mutual understanding, too bad.
積んだ経験の因果が形骸化された
The karma of accumulated experience is hollowed out.
私は退屈の進化 あきちゃった
I am the evolution of boredom, I'm tired of it.
ナンセンス 偏ったグラグラ
Nonsense, biased and shaky.
すかされていくみたい
It feels like it's fading away.
すい尽くして あれもこれもそれも
Draining everything, this, that, and the other.
同じ味がする UNDEAD
They all taste the same, UNDEAD.
信じられない お前と前の連鎖
Unbelievable chain of you and the past.
いつの世も 過去も未来も今にあるんだ<
In every era, past and future exist in the present.
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill the duty of living with honest devotion.
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending!
信じたい お前と生きている
I want to believe I'm living with you.
幸せを諦めてしまうなんて 嘘であれ
Let it be a lie that we've given up on happiness.
ただ苦しみになれ 堪えているだけじゃ
Just becoming pain, if we're only holding it in...
死んでるも同然 屍のアンデッド
it's as good as dead, a corpse of an undead!
A happy...
A lucky...
Be happy...
UNDEAD
目を逸らした過去も
Even the past we turned away from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future,
全部全部お前のもの
everything, all of it, belongs to you.
古今東西 ピースピース
All times and places, peace peace!
Ah, the future
Can't change the past
But the future
Love for the future
人並みところ
Just like anyone else,
いつもラッキーこと
always lucky,
ここんとうざいピースピース
all times and places, peace peace!
愛♡スクリーム！
Love Scream!
教えてもっと あなたのこと
Tell me more about you.
聴かせてもっと あなたの声
Let me hear more of your voice.
高鳴るドキドキ もう止められない
This pounding heartbeat can't be stopped anymore.
Oh, I need you! Oh, I need you!
友達は卒業 運命の私
Graduating from being friends, my destiny.
見つけてほしいな
I want you to find me.
勇気を出して！
Have courage!
two
見つめる作戦
Our staring strategy
three
目と目が合えば
If our eyes meet
four
止められない
There's no stopping it
yeah, yeah, yeah この恋 この愛で
Yeah, yeah, yeah, with this love and affection
melt, melty 溶けちゃうよ
Melt, melty, I'm going to melt away
ねぇ？ ねぇ？ ねぇ？ 気づいて my darling
Hey? Hey? Hey? Notice me, my darling
届け！ 大好き！
Reach him! I love you!
アイ愛、スクリーム scream 叫びましょう
Ai-love, scream! Scream, let's shout it out
スクリーム！ アイスクリーム！
Scream! Ice cream!
ok! アイ愛、スクリーム！ scream 叫びましょう
OK! Ai-love, scream! Scream, let's shout it out
スクリーム！ アイスクリーム！
Scream! Ice cream!
かるびちゃん！
Karubi-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
チョコミントよりもあなた！
Even more than chocolate mint, I like you!
ぷるちゃん！
Puru-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
ストロベリーフレーバーよりもあなた！
Even more than strawberry flavor, I like you!
あきちゃん！
Aki-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
クッキー＆クリームよりもあなた！
Even more than cookies and cream, I like you!
みんな！
Everyone!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
もちろん大好きアイスクリーム！
Of course, our favorite, ice cream!
止められない
There's no stopping it
yeah, yeah, yeah この恋 この愛で
Yeah, yeah, yeah, with this love and affection
melt, melty 溶けちゃうよ
Melt, melty, I'm going to melt away
ねぇ？ ねぇ？ ねぇ？ 気づいて my darling
Hey? Hey? Hey? Notice me, my darling
届け！ 大好き！
Reach him! I love you!
アイ愛、スクリーム scream 叫びましょう
Ai-love, scream! Scream, let's shout it out
スクリーム！ アイスクリーム！
Scream! Ice cream!
ok!
アイ愛、スクリーム！ scream 叫びましょう
Ai-love, scream! Scream, let's shout it out
スクリーム！ アイスクリーム！
Scream! Ice cream!
おねがい 見つけて my darling
Please find me, my darling
おねがい 気づいて my darling
Please notice me, my darling
one
勇気を出して
Gathering up my courage
two
近づく作戦
Our getting-closer strategy
three
手と手が見つめ合って
Our hands touching
four
止められない
There's no stopping it
yeah, yeah, yeah この恋 この愛で
Yeah, yeah, yeah, with this love and affection
melt, melty 溶けちゃうよ
Melt, melty, I'm going to melt away
ねぇ？ ねぇ？ ねぇ？ 気づいて my darling
Hey? Hey? Hey? Notice me, my darling
それは！ アナタ！
That person is... you!
アイ愛、スクリーム scream 叫びましょう
Ai-love, scream! Scream, let's shout it out
スクリーム！ アイスクリーム！
Scream! Ice cream!
ok!
アイ愛、スクリーム！ scream 叫びましょう
Ai-love, scream! Scream, let's shout it out
スクリーム！ アイスクリーム！
Scream! Ice cream!
アイ愛、スクリーム scream 叫びましょう
Ai-love, scream! Scream, let's shout it out
スクリーム！ アイスクリーム！
Scream! Ice cream!
ok!
アイ愛、スクリーム！ scream 叫びましょう
Ai-love, scream! Scream, let's shout it out
スクリーム！ アイスクリーム！
Scream! Ice cream!
la, la, la, la, la, love, love
元気もらえて面白くって、オレンジで
Getting energy, super fun, orange themed...
シャンパンコール得意な人いないかな？
I wonder if there is anyone who is good at champagne calls?
それオレじゃないかーーい！
Isn't that me?!
イケナイ太陽
[Title: Ikenai Taiyou]
Na na na na na na na na na
チョットでいいから 見せてくれないか
Won't you show me, even if it's just a little bit?
お前のセクシー・フェロモンで オレ メロメロ
I'm falling head over heels for your sexy pheromones
ふれちゃいそう でも イケナイの！
It looks like I'm going to touch you, but I can't!
徐々に高なる鼓動 とめられないわ
Little by little, my heart beats faster, I can't stop it
交わす言葉の 記憶遠く
Memories of the words we exchange are fading away...
動きに揺れ動く
...swaying with the movement.
濡れた髪を撫でた
I stroked your wet hair,
そして Ah...
and then, ah...
A B C
続かない そんなんじゃダメじゃない
doesn't continue. That's no good, is it?
だって心の内は違うんじゃない？
Because deep down in your heart, isn't it different?
俺の青春 そんなもんじゃない
My youth isn't anything like that.
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to burn up deep inside.
きっとキミじゃなきゃやだよ
It has to be you, no one else will do.
俺はイケナイ太陽
I'm the naughty sun.
Na na na...
Ah...
「赤い糸」なんて絵空事
A "red thread of fate" is just a fantasy,
でも下心でさえ信じたいの
but I want to believe even if it's just an ulterior motive.
俺は正しい キミも正しい
I am right, and you are right.
とにかくもう左右されないぜ
In any case, we won't be swayed anymore.
騙し騙され胸うずく
Deceiving and being deceived, our hearts ache.
下手な芝居がより盛り上げる夜
This clumsy acting only hypes up the night.
息が耳に触れた二人
Our breaths brushing against each other's ears...
Ah...
A B C
続かない そんなんじゃダメじゃない
doesn't continue. That's no good, is it?
だって心の内は違うんじゃない？
Because deep down in your heart, isn't it different?
あたしの青春 そんなもんじゃない
My youth isn't anything like that.
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to burn up deep inside.
きっとキミじゃなきゃやだよ
It has to be you, no one else will do.
あたしイケナイ太陽
I'm a naughty sun.
Whoo! Whoo!
交わす言葉の記憶遠く
The memories of the words we exchange fade away,
口元の動きに揺れ動く
swaying with the movement of your mouth.
濡れた髪を撫でた
I stroked your wet hair,
そして Ah...
and then, ah...
Ah...
A B C
続かない そんなんじゃダメじゃない
doesn't continue. That's no good, is it?
だって心の内は違うんじゃない？
Because deep down in your heart, isn't it different?
俺の青春 そんなもんじゃない
My youth isn't anything like that.
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to burn up deep inside.
きっとキミじゃなきゃやだよ
It has to be you, no one else will do.
俺はイケナイ太陽
I'm the naughty sun.
絡み合う糸はキミと
The intertwined thread...
俺を結ぶ赤い糸
...is the red thread that connects you and me.
Na na na...
Ah...
はぁ、はぁ...
Haah, haah...
うわー！
Wow!
みんなー！
Everyone!
来てくれて...
Thank you for coming...
ありがとう！
...thank you so much!
ということで、お友達が来てくれたので
And so, since my friends came over today,
せっかくなので自己紹介してもらおうと思います！
I'd like to have them introduce themselves!
まずはプルルちゃんから！
First up, Pururu-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
おはぷる！
Oha-puru!
天使と悪魔のぷるぷるエンジェルデビル、あくまのぷるるです！
The jiggly angel-devil of angels and demons, Akuma no Pururu!
ぷるるです！
I'm Pururu!
アキちゃん！お誕生日おめでとう！
Aki-chan! Happy birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
えっ、とってもとっても楽しかったです！
I had so, so much fun!
最高！
You're the best!
そして、続いてかるびちゃん！
And next, Karubi-chan!
はい！お肉の国のお姫様、赤見かるびです！
Yes! The princess of the Meat Kingdom, Akami Karubi!
火傷するぜ！
You're gonna get burned!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
いい波乗って！
Ride the good wave!
友達のライブ初めてだからさ、マジで嬉しかったよ！
This is my first time at a friend's live, so I'm really happy!
呼んでくれてありがとう！
Thank you for inviting me!
またやろうぜ！
Let's do it again!
またやろう！
Let's!
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
そして、最後に、ずずさん！
And finally, Zuzu-san!
はい！僕のこと知らない人いると思うんで、自己紹介だけさせてください！
Yes! Since some people might not know me, let me introduce myself!
きた！
Here it comes!
雨降ってザーザー 少女時代はGee Gee
When it rains, it pours. Girls' Generation goes Gee Gee!
俺の名前は、ず、ず、ず、ず、ず、ずずでございます！
My name is Zu-zu-zu-zu-zu- Zuzu!
アキさん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Aki-san, happy birthday!
はぁ、楽しい！
Ah, that was fun!
疲れた、疲れたね
I'm exhausted.
お疲れ様でした！
Thank you for your hard work!
お忙しい人気者だ！
You're a busy, popular one!
お忙しい！
So busy!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ああ、賑やかで楽しかった。
Ah, that was so lively and fun.
JANE DOE / 作詞・作曲：米津玄師
JANE DOE / Lyrics & Composition: Kenshi Yonezu
まるで この世界で
It feels like, in this world...
二人だけみたいだね
...it's just the two of us.
なんて 少しだけ
How I let myself...
夢を見てしまっただけ
...dream a little bit.
つま先に月明かり
Moonlight on my toes,
花束の香り
the scent of a bouquet,
君に触れる指
fingers touching you.
さよなら もう行かなきゃ
Goodbye, I have to go now,
何もかも 忘れて
forgetting everything.
硝子の上を 裸足のまま歩く
Walking barefoot on glass,
痛むごとに 血が流れて落ちていく
with every painful step, blood flows and drips away.
お願い その赤い足跡を
Please, follow those red footprints...
辿って 会いに来て
...and come to find me.
錆びたプールに 放たれていく金魚
Goldfish released into a rusty pool,
靴箱の中 隠した林檎
an apple hidden in the shoe box,
萎びた君の肌に 残る傷跡
the scars left on your withered skin,
犬のように 泳いだ迷子
a lost dog swimming.
どこにいるの
Where are you?
(ここにいるよ)
(I'm right here.)
何をしてるの
What are you doing?
(ずっと見てるよ)
(I'm always watching you.)
この世を間違いで満たそう
Let's fill this world with mistakes.
側にいてよ
Stay by my side,
遊びに行こうよ
let's go have some fun.
どこに いるの
Where are you?
硝子の上を 裸足のまま歩く
Walking barefoot on glass,
痛むごとに 血が流れて落ちていく
with every painful step, blood flows and drips away.
お願い その赤い足跡を
Please, follow those red footprints...
辿って 会いに来て
...and come to find me.
まるで この世界で
It feels like, in this world...
二人だけみたいだね
...it's just the two of us.
なんて 少しだけ
How I let myself...
夢を見てしまっただけ
...dream a little bit.
さあ、選択の時だ。
Now, it's time to choose.
コイン。
Coin.
はぁ... このコインは...
Ah... This coin is...
はぁ、そうか。君はそっちなんだね。
Ah, I see. You're on that side.
そっち？
That side?
ここに座って。
Sit here.
え？
Eh?
この後は、君次第だよ。
After this, it's up to you.
忘れられないのは この目のせい
It's these eyes' fault that I can't forget
赤く残る過ち 甘噛みの跡
The red stains of my errors, the traces of your play-biting.
溢れだす愛は 止めともない
The overflowing love doesn't even have an end.
誰もいない間に 悪魔を探す
While there's no one else around, I search for the devil.
作り笑いは この耳のせい
It's these ears' fault that my smiles are strained.
深い壁の中 から呼びかける声
From within the thick walls, a voice calls out to me.
Whisper Whisper Whisper まだ触らせない
Whisper, whisper, whisper, but I still won't let you touch.
この檻を抜け出して 悪魔は駆ける
The devil breaks out of this cage and races away.
鏡の前で この口のせい
It's this mouth's fault that I'm in front of the mirror,
伝えたい言葉さえ 噛み殺す夜
Stifling even the words I want to say tonight.
Whisper Whisper Whisper まだ打ち明けない
Whisper, whisper, whisper, but I still won't open my heart.
神様を裏切って 悪魔と過ごす
I turn my back on God and while away time with the devil.
曖昧に夢見ていたい あなたに
I want to dream vaguely, and to you...
そっと気づかせてあげたいだけ...
I just want to gently make you realize, that's all.
Oh あなたにも Oh あなたにも Oh あなたにも
Oh, even you... Oh, even you... Oh, even you...
消えない傷を隠したい あなたに
I want to hide my unfading scars, and to you...
そっと悩ませてあげたいだけ...
I just want to gently make you worry, that's all.
Oh あなたにも Oh あなたにも
Oh, even you... Oh, even you...
悪魔を探す
I'm searching for the devil.
作り笑いは この耳のせい
It's these ears' fault that my smiles are strained.
深い壁の中 から呼びかける声
From within the thick walls, a voice calls out to me.
Whisper Whisper Whisper まだ触らせない
Whisper, whisper, whisper, but I still won't let you touch.
この檻を抜け出して 悪魔は駆ける
The devil breaks out of this cage and races away.
鏡の前で この口のせい
It's this mouth's fault that I'm in front of the mirror,
伝えたい言葉さえ 噛み殺す夜
Stifling even the words I want to say tonight.
Whisper Whisper Whisper まだ打ち明けない
Whisper, whisper, whisper, but I still won't open my heart.
神様を裏切って 悪魔と過ごす
I turn my back on God and while away time with the devil.
好き嫌い常識 I don't care 吹っ飛べ BANG!!!
Likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care, fly away BANG!!!
かかってこい majority あたしに負けはなし
Bring it on, majority, I'll never lose.
ここまでって引かれたそのボーダー 誰のルール？
Whose rule is that border drawn right here?
あの日のり越えた weak heart
That weak heart I overcame that day,
強くなったあたしが笑い飛ばしてあげる はは
the stronger me will just laugh it away, haha!
言いたい事は言う やりたくない事はしない
I say what I want to say, I don't do what I don't want to do.
悪意気にしない 皆違うの当然だし
I don't care about malice, it's natural everyone is different.
あたしも変わんない ニューノーマル時代
I haven't changed either, in this new normal era.
Everybody, say "I want to be free"
Yesもnoも言わない それじゃ何も変えられない
Saying neither yes nor no won't change anything.
Everybody, say "I want to live more"
叶えたい自分肯定 生きているんだあたし
Affirming the self I want to achieve, I'm alive!
ねぇ 生きているんだあたし
Hey, I'm alive!
歌えや歌え今を （声上げて）\
Sing, sing the present (raise your voice)!
生まれたその時から選んできたんだ
I've chosen this since the moment I was born.
思い出せあたしはあたしだ
Remember, I am me.
不可能な事など何一つない 嘘じゃない
There is no such thing as an impossible thing, no lie,
なりたい自分に\
to the self I want to be.
好き嫌い常識 I don't care 吹っ飛べ BANG!!!
Likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care, fly away BANG!!!
Again
好き嫌い常識 I don't care 吹っ飛べ BANG!!!
Likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care, fly away BANG!!!
フル10鳴らす このリリックかます
Blast it to ten, drop this lyric,
わからす挑発 下向いて舌打ちからの「は？」
make them understand, provocation, looking down clicking my tongue going "Ha?"
Excuse me あしからず 倍返し
Excuse me, pardon me, payback!
聞かせてあげる
I'll let you hear it.
やってらんないわ
I can't stand this anymore!
アタシがついてるから
Because you've got me!
Everybody say, "I want to be free"
喰らう このビート囚監 全部黙らすわ
Devouring this beat, shutting everyone up!
Everybody say...
目覚めさせてあげる
I will awaken you!
アタシ
Me!
ねぇ 聞いてんの？アタシ
Hey, are you listening to me?
アタシ
Me!
生まれた...
I was born...
衝動に駆られ 選んできたんだ
driven by impulse, I have chosen!
思い出せ アタシはアタシだ
Remember, I am myself!
不可能なことなど
There is nothing impossible...
何一つもない さあ 立ち上がれ
absolutely nothing, so rise up!
生まれた衝動に駆られ 選んできたんだ
Driven by impulse of birth, I have chosen!
思い出せ アナタはアナタだ
Remember, you are yourself!
不可能なことなど
There is nothing impossible...
何一つもない さあ 立ち上がれ
absolutely nothing, so rise up!
目一杯自分に
With all my might, to myself!
Hate, Love, Hate, Trust, Hate, I don't care, Foot on the gas!
Bad Apple!!
流れてく時の中ででも
Even within the flowing passage of time,
気だるさがほら グルグル回って
look, listlessness keeps spinning round and round.
私から離れる心も見えないわ
I can't even see my heart drifting away from me.
そう知らない
That's right, I don't know.
自分から動くこともなく
Without even moving on my own,
時の隙間に流され続けて
I continue to be swept away in the gaps of time.
知らないわ 周りのことなど
I don't know anything about my surroundings,
私は私 それだけ
I am just myself, and that's all.
夢見てる なにを見てない
Am I dreaming? I see nothing,
語るも無駄な 自分の言葉
my own words are pointless to speak.
悲しむなんて 疲れだけよ
Feeling sad only wears me out,
何も感じず 過ごせばいいの
it's best to live feeling nothing at all.
戸惑う言葉 与えられても
Even if I am given bewildering words,
自分の心 ただ上の空
my heart is just somewhere else.
もし私から 動くのならば
If I were to make a move myself,
すべて変えるのなら 黒にする
and if I were to change everything, I'd make it black.
こんな自分に 未来はあるの？
Is there a future for someone like me?
こんな世界に 私はいるの？
Am I really in a world like this?
今切ないの？ 今悲しいの？
Am I in pain now? Am I sad now?
自分のことも 分からないまま
Without even understanding myself.
歩むことさえ 疲れだけよ
Even just walking only wears me out,
人のことなど 知りもしないわ
and I don't know a thing about anyone else.
こんな私に 変われるのなら
If even someone like me could change,
もし変われるのなら 白になる
if I could change, I would turn to white.
流れてく時の中ででも
Even within the flowing passage of time,
気だるさがほら グルグル回って
look, listlessness keeps spinning round and round.
悲しむなんて 疲れるだけよ
Grieving is just tiring...
何も感じず 過ごせばいいの
It's fine to just get by without feeling anything.
戸惑う言葉 与えられても
Even if confusing words are given to me,
自分の心 ただ上の空
My own heart is just in the clouds.
もし私から 動くのならば
If I were to make a move myself,
すべて変えるのなら 黒にする
If I'm to change everything, I'd turn it to black.
動くのならば 動くのならば
If I were to move, if I were to move...
すべて壊すわ すべて壊すわ
I'll destroy everything, I'll destroy everything!
悲しむならば 悲しむならば
If I were to grieve, if I were to grieve...
私の心 白く変われる?
Could my heart change to white?
貴方のことも 私のことも
Whether it's about you, or about me,
全てのことも まだ知らないの
Or about everything, I still don't know.
重い目蓋を 開けたのならば
If I were to open my heavy eyelids...
すべて壊すのなら 黒になれ
If I'm to destroy everything, let it turn black!
いつか君が瞳に灯す愛の光が
One day, the light of love you light in your eyes
時を超えて
will transcend time...
滅び急ぐ世界の夢を 確かに一つ
And surely destroy one of the dreams of a world
壊すだろう
that is rushing toward its demise.
躊躇いを飲み干して
Swallow down your hesitation.
君が望むものは何?
What is it that you desire?
こんな欲深い憧れの行方に
On the path of such a greedy yearning,
儚い明日はあるの?
is there a fleeting tomorrow?
子供の頃 夢に見てた
Like the ancient magic
古の魔法のように
I used to dream about as a child,
闇さえ砕く力で
with a power that can even shatter darkness,
微笑む君に会いたい
I want to meet you smiling.
怯えるこの手の中には
Within these trembling hands
手折られた花の勇気
is the courage of a plucked flower.
想いだけが頼る全て
Our feelings are all we can rely on
光を呼び覚ます
to awaken the light...
願い
Our wish.
いつか君も誰かの為に
One day, you too will surely desire
強い力を望むのだろう
a great power for the sake of someone else.
愛が胸を捉えた夜に
On the night love captured your heart,
未知の言葉が生まれて来る
unfamiliar words will be born.
迷わずずにいけるなら
If I can go on without hesitation,
心が砕けてもいいわ
I wouldn't mind even if my heart shatters.
いつも目の前の哀しみに
I want a spell
立ち向かう為の呪文が欲しい
to confront the sorrow always in front of me.
君はまだ夢見る記憶
You are still a memory in a dream,
私は眠らない明日
while I am a sleepless tomorrow.
二人が出会う奇跡を
To seize the miracle
勝ち取る為に進むわ
of our meeting, I will march forward.
怯えるこの手の中には
Within these trembling hands
手折られた花の刃
is the blade of a plucked flower.
想いだけが生きる全て保存
Our feelings are all we have to live for,
心に振りかざす
brandishing them in our hearts...
願い
Our wish.
囚われた太陽の輝く
The captured sun shines...
不思議の国の本が好きだった頃
Back when I loved books about Wonderland,
願いはきっと叶うと
believing that wishes
教えるおとぎ話を信じた
would surely come true, as fairy tales taught,
光と影の中
within the light and shadow...
静かに咲き乱れていた古の魔法を優しく
The ancient magic that quietly bloomed in full glory gently
世界を変える力がその手にあると囁く
whispers that the power to change the world is in your hands.
終わらない夢を見よう
Let us dream an endless dream
君と行く時のなかで
within the flow of time spent with you,
想いだけが生きるすべて
where our feelings alone are everything to live for
命を作るのは願い
and wishes are what create life.
わー！
Yay!
アキちゃん！お誕生日おめでとう！
Aki-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとう！イェーイ！
Thank you! Yay!
今日は来てくれて本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for coming today.
こちらこそですよ！呼んでくれてありがとう！
The pleasure is ours! Thank you for inviting us!
実はね、二人を呼んだのはちょっと理由があって。
Actually, there's a reason why I invited the two of you.
おー！なんだなんだ？
Oh! What is it, what is it?
前に、アキロゼの4周年の時に、3人でカラフィナさんの曲を歌わせてもらったんだけど。
Before, during Akirose's 4th anniversary, the three of us sang a Kalafina song.
やりようですね！めちゃくちゃ良かったよね。
Indeed we did! That was incredibly good.
ハーモニーがね！ / そう！
The harmony was amazing! / Yes!
もうね、ミオちゃんの歌も大好きだし、ロボ子さんの歌も大好きだし、ずっとね、忘れられないの、それが。
I love Mio-chan's singing, and I love Roboco-san's singing too, and I just couldn't forget that performance.
わかる！わかる！めっちゃわかる！
I get it! I totally get it!
そう！だからもう1回、このライブステージで3人歌いたくて、今日は来てもらいました！
Right! So, wanting us to sing together on this live stage again, I asked you to come today!
嬉しい！ありがとう！
We're so happy! Thank you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
そう、だから、これからは、これを機に、もっと何か3人で歌いたりとか、そういうの挑戦できたらめっちゃ嬉しい！
So, starting from this, I'd be really happy if we could challenge ourselves to sing more as a trio!
いいですね！ハーモニーを重ねていきましょうよ！
That sounds great! Let's layer our harmonies!
えー！いいよ！嬉しい！
Yes! Absolutely! I'm so happy!
ユニット名とか欲しいな。
I'd love for us to have a unit name.
確かに！欲しい！えー、なんだろう？
True! We need one! What should it be?
なんかちょっと、世界目指せるくらいのさ！
Something that can let us aim for the world!
世界？！
The world?!
世界の、世界のコンサートしようよ！
Let's hold a world, a world concert!
したい！世界に届く何かをね！
I want to! Something that reaches the world!
したいということで、3人でライブとか、アコースティックとか...
And so, since we want to do that, maybe a live show, acoustic...
オーケストラライブとか！
Or an orchestral concert!
わー！良くないですか、そんなこともしてみたい。
Wow! Wouldn't that be great? I want to try that too.
我らならできるかもしれない！
With us, we might just be able to do it!
おねがいします！
Please make it happen!
あれ？これは一体何ですか？
Huh? What on earth is this?
あ、も、もしかして...
Ah, c-could it be...
このライブで、みんなからの、なんかいいパワーで...
With everyone's good power from this live show...
なんかいいパワー？！なんかいいパワー来てる！儀式じゃんそれ！
Some good power?! Good power is coming! That's like a ritual!
何なんだよ、そのパワー！
What is that power anyway?!
こちらがなんと、完成しました！
This is, believe it or not, completed!
何それ？！
What is that?!
実は、このあと、アキロゼの新曲が出ます！
Actually, right after this, Akirose's new song will be out!
わー！出た！やったー！
Wow! It's out! Yay!
こちら、今回のライブのテーマというか、壮大なテーマがあるんですけど、そちらが詰まったような楽曲になっています。
This is like the theme of this live concert, featuring a grand theme packed into this song.
そして、ライブ終わりの日付が変わる時にリリースしますので、ぜひ聴いてください！
And it will be released as the date changes right after the live, so please listen to it!
聴いてねー！みんな聴こう！
Listen to it! Everyone, let's listen!
ではでは、次の曲に行きますか？
Then, shall we move on to the next song?
次の曲？
The next song?
はい！新曲のお披露目...
Yes! The reveal of the new song...
え、何だって？！
Wait, what?!
しちゃいます！
...will happen now!
え、今からってこと？！
Wait, you mean right now?!
今から頑張ります！
Yes, I'll do my best right now!
最後まで見逃せないですね！楽しみ！
We can't miss a single moment until the end! I'm excited!
じゃあアキちゃん、頑張ってね！
Then, Aki-chan, do your best!
ありがとう！頑張るよ！
Thank you! I will!
魅惑の言葉の
Behind the alluring words,
裏面に忍ばせた
hidden on the other side...
1mgのスパイス
is just a milligram of spice.
たちまち華麗に
Instantly and elegantly,
指先で彩る
I color it with my fingertips.
本日のダイス
Today's roll of the dice.
辺り見て妥協してちゃ
If you look around and compromise,
生き残れないでしょう
you won't survive, will you?
率直に言って
To be completely frank,
全てが欲しい
I want everything.
一人勝ちにオールイン
Going all-in to win it all!
どうなっちゃってもいいじゃない
What does it matter what happens to me?
際限なんてないじゃない
There are absolutely no limits!
翻弄して 翻弄されて
Toying with others, being toyed with,
ゾク、ゾク
thrilled to the bone.
喰らっちゃっても本望でしょ
Even if I'm consumed, it's what I want.
最低だって滾るでしょ
Even if it's the worst, it gets the blood pumping!
見透かして 見透かされて
Seeing right through, being seen right through,
故に終わりは無い
so there will never be an end.
高鳴るこの全て ノンフィクション
Everything that makes my heart race is non-fiction!
嗜むはずでも
Though I only meant to enjoy a little,
たまには飲みすぎて
sometimes I drink way too much.
1回休み
Lose one turn.
周りもザワつく
The crowd starts buzzing,
思わぬうたた寝で
as I unexpectedly drift off to sleep.
2回休み
Lose two turns.
切れる頭と勘だけじゃ
Just sharp brains and intuition
手に入らないモノ
won't get you what you want.
速攻で射て 逃されるならいい
Shoot to kill instantly—if it gets away, so be it.
命懸けで楽しむわ
I'm going to risk my life to have fun!
天と地は案外近い
Heaven and earth are surprisingly close.
この通り 命代わり
This is how it goes, my life is on the line.
されど大往生
But what a glorious end it will be!
秘める想い 此宵も 私は強い
With hidden feelings, tonight, I am strong!
どうなっちゃってもいいじゃない
What does it matter what happens to me?
際限なんてないじゃない
There are absolutely no limits!
翻弄して 翻弄されて
Toying with others, being toyed with,
ゾク、ゾク
thrilled to the bone.
喰らっちゃっても本望でしょ
Even if I'm consumed, it's what I want.
最低だって滾るでしょ
Even if it's the worst, it gets the blood pumping!
見透かして 見透かされて
Seeing right through, being seen right through,
故に終わりは無い
so there will never be an end.
高鳴るこの全て ノンフィクション
Everything that makes my heart race is non-fiction!
墜ちても 昇っても ノンフィクション
Whether falling or rising, it's all non-fiction!
中川に浮かぶ 夕日をめがけて
Aiming for the sunset floating over Nakagawa River,
小石を蹴ったら 靴まで飛んで
I kicked a pebble and my shoe went flying, too.
ジョギングしていた 大工の頭領に
A carpenter boss who was jogging by
ガキのまんまだと 笑われたのさ
laughed at me, saying I'm still just a kid.
どこかに元気を 落っことしても
Even if I lose my high spirits somewhere,
葛飾亀有 アクビをひとつ
here in Katsushika Kameari, I just let out a yawn.
変わらない町並みが 妙にやさしいよ
This unchanging townscape is strangely comforting.
中央広場で 子供の手を引く
Holding a child's hand at the central plaza,
太ったあの娘は 初恋の彼女
that plump girl was my first love.
ゴンパチ池で 渡したラブレター
The love letter I handed her at Gonpachi Pond,
今も持ってると からかわれたよ
she teased me, saying she still has it.
何にもいいこと なかったけど
Even though nothing particularly good happened,
葛飾水元 流れる雲と
under the drifting clouds of Katsushika Mizumoto,
ラプソディー口ずさみ 少し歩こうか
hum a rhapsody and let's walk a little.
カラスが鳴くから もう日が暮れるね
The crows are crying, so the sun is setting.
焼鳥ほうばり ビール飲もうか
Shall we stuff our faces with yakitori and have a beer?
トンガリ帽子の
From the pointy-hat
取水塔から
water intake tower,
帝釈天へと
down towards Taishakuten,
夕陽が落ちる
the evening sun sinks.
明日もこうして 終わるんだね
Tomorrow will end just like this too,
葛飾柴又 幸せだって
in Katsushika Shibamata, even when I said I was happy.
なくして気がついた バカな女だから
I only realized after losing it, because I'm a foolish woman.
どこかに元気を 落っことしても
Even if I lose my energy somewhere,
葛飾亀有 アクビをひとつ
in Katsushika Kameari, I let out a yawn.
変わらない町並みが 妙にやさしいよ
The unchanging townscape is strangely comforting.
アキビ生誕祭2026をご覧の皆様、いかがでしたでしょうか？
Everyone watching Akibi Birthday Festival 2026, how did you enjoy it?
さあ、ここからは大事なお知らせがあるから、最後までしっかり聞いていってね！
Now, I have some important announcements, so make sure to listen closely until the very end!
まずは、お知らせ一つ目！
First up, the first announcement!
アキロゼ生誕2026、誕生日グッズ発売です！
Akirose Birthday 2026 merchandise is now on sale!
今回はライブの世界観をぎゅっと楽しんでもらえるグッズを頑張って制作いたしました。
This time, we worked hard to create merch that lets you fully enjoy the world of the concert.
なので、今回のライブが良かったなーって思った方はぜひ応援で購入していただくのもすごく嬉しいです！
So, if you thought today's concert was great, I'd be so happy if you could show your support by buying them!
それでは、まず一つ目のグッズ！Life is GAME ラバーマット！
Now for the first item! The "Life is GAME" rubber mat!
今回のイラストはLAM先生に描き下ろしていただきました。素敵なイラストありがとうございます！
This illustration was specially drawn by LAM-sensei. Thank you for the wonderful illustration!
今回のライブの世界観をイメージしたイラストになっています。
This illustration is inspired by the world of today's concert.
めちゃくちゃセクシーで色っぽいけど、かっこいいようなアキロゼになっています。
It shows an Akirose who is super sexy and alluring, yet also cool.
ラバーマットで思う存分楽しんでください。
Please enjoy it to your heart's content with this rubber mat.
ちなみにサイズはカードゲームにぴったり！
By the way, the size is perfect for card games!
この意味、わかるよね？
You know what that means, right?
二つ目のグッズが、
The second item is...
運命の5枚 タロット風アクリルスタンドセット！
the "5 Cards of Destiny: Tarot-style Acrylic Stand Set"!
アキロゼがあなたのことを占って背中を押してあげます。
Akirose will read your fortune and give you a gentle push forward.
一日の始まりや、何か運命を託したいみたいなそんな時に
At the start of your day, or when you want to leave things to fate,
使って楽しむ、そして5枚バーンって飾っておけるので、見ても楽しめるようになっております。
you can play with them, or display all five prominently to enjoy them visually too.
占い方法は、この後紹介するアキロゼのASMRボイスと連動しております。
The fortune-telling system links up with Akirose's ASMR voice pack, which I'll introduce next.
飾っても楽しい、使っても楽しい、そのような連動グッズになっているので、ぜひゲットしてください！
They're fun to display and fun to use, so please grab yours!
続いてのグッズは、アキロゼのトランプ！
The next item is "Akirose's Playing Cards"!
作っちゃいました！
I actually made them!
こちら、実際に遊んでいただけるトランプなので、
Since you can actually play games with these cards,
たくさん、予備も買った方がいいんじゃないかなーと思います！
I think it might be a good idea to buy multiple decks, even a spare one!
ぜひトランプでもアキロゼをたくさん楽しんで、アピールもしてくださいね。
Please enjoy seeing Akirose on these cards and show them off to everyone.
続いては、こちら！
Next up is this!
アキロゼのカードケース！
The "Akirose Card Case"!
これはもちろん、トランプなど小物入れても大丈夫です。
Of course, you can also use this to store playing cards or other small items.
ぜひおうちや、持ち歩きに使ってね。
Please use it at home or carry it around with you.
そして、ボイスの紹介です。
And now, let me introduce the voice packs.
今回もASMRボイスを特別に発売！
We are specially releasing ASMR voice packs this time too!
アキとロゼがそれぞれ左右からあなたのことを誘惑しちゃうかも。
Aki and Rose might whisper from both sides to tempt you.
台本も頑張って書いたので、ぜひぜひたっぷり楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです。
I worked hard writing the script myself, so I really hope you enjoy it fully.
こちらボイスは「Life is GAME〜アキロゼの盤上〜」こちらをメインとし、
The main voice track is "Life is GAME: On Akirose's Board",
ASMRショートボイスとして、先ほどの「運命の5枚 タロット風アクリルカード」と連動したショートボイスが入っております。
and there are also ASMR short voices linked to the "5 Cards of Destiny: Tarot-style Acrylic Cards" mentioned earlier.
ショートボイスのシャッフル・ランダム再生をして選ばれたボイスが、あなたの運命の1枚になります。ぜひ色々楽しんでね！
By shuffling and randomly playing these short voices, the voice you pull will be your card of destiny. Please have fun with it!
これらのグッズ全てが詰まったフルセット購入には、なんと特典もついております。
Purchasing the full set containing all of these items also comes with a special bonus!
今回のキービジュアルのイラストを使ったチケット風カードになっております。
It's a ticket-style card featuring this concert's key visual illustration.
「あなたは、このゲームに参加する？」参加したい？
"Will you join this game?" Do you want to join?
こちらもライブの世界観を高めるアイテムになっているので、ぜひゲットしてください。
This is also an item designed to immerse you further into the concert's world, so please get it.
そして、数量限定あります。
Also, there is a limited-quantity version.
直筆サインと箔押し複製メッセージが入ったものになっております。頑張って書きます！
It features a handwritten signature and a foil-stamped printed message. I'll do my best to write them!
そして、数量限定が終わり次第、箔押しでの複製サインとメッセージが入ったチケット風カードになります。
Once the limited-quantity version is sold out, it will be a ticket-style card with a foil-stamped printed signature and message.
ぜひフルセット購入特典ゲットしてね。
Please make sure to get the full set purchase bonus.
大切な発売時間は、この後21時30分！21時30分にショップオープンです！
The important release time is tonight at 21:30! The shop opens at 21:30!
ぜひ登録など準備して備えておいてね。
Please get ready by signing up beforehand so you're prepared.
続きまして、お知らせ二つ目！
Moving on to the second announcement!
この後、21時45分からメンバー限定のアフターライブを行います！
After this, starting from 21:45, we will hold a members-only after-show concert!
ライブ本編とまた違う楽曲を披露する予定なので、ぜひお楽しみに！
I plan to perform different songs from the main concert, so please look forward to it!
今日メンバーになった方もぜひぜひ見てね。
Those who became members today, please be sure to watch it too.
ちなみに、過去のライブのメンバー限定、
By the way, the members-only archives of past concerts...
アライブもね、見れちゃうと思うので、
I think you can watch the archive as well, so...
ぜひその辺りも見てみてね！
please be sure to check that out too!
ちなみに今回のサムネイルイラストは、
By the way, the thumbnail illustration for this event...
メンバー限定で壁紙としてプレゼント予定です！
will be given to members as a wallpaper!
お楽しみに！
Look forward to it!
そして、お知らせ3つ目！
And now, the third announcement!
本日の生誕祭ライブの後も...
Even after today's Birthday Live...
お楽しみはまだまだ続きます！
the fun is far from over!
なんと！ホロアースにて特別企画、
We actually have a special event in Holoearth!
アキ・ローゼンタール 生誕祭2020 アンコール...
Aki Rosenthal Birthday Live 2020 Encore...
in ホロアースを開催します！
will be held in Holoearth!
今回、初披露した新曲『モノポリー』をホロアースで歌います！
I will sing my newly debuted song, "Monopoly", in Holoearth!
いろんな角度からアキロゼのパフォーマンスや演出をじっくりと見てみてくださいね！
Please take a close look at AkiRose's performance and stage effects from various angles!
さらに、ホロアースだけのMCパートもたっぷりあるので、ぜひぜひ会いに来てください！
Plus, there will be plenty of Holoearth-exclusive MC parts, so please come see me!
開催日は3月13日、3月13日です！
The event date is March 13th! March 13th!
詳細はホロアース公式Xをチェックしてね！
Check the official Holoearth X account for details!
そして、最後のお知らせが...
And now, for the final announcement...
新曲『モノポリー』！
My new song, "Monopoly"!
本日、日付が変わる頃にリリースされますので、
It will be released today when the clock strikes midnight,...
各音楽配信サービスからぜひ購入してね！
so please buy it from any music streaming service!
たくさん聴いてね！
Listen to it a lot, okay?!
振り付けも、歌もとってもキャッチーなので、覚えてみんなで楽しんでもらえる...
The choreography and song are super catchy, so I hope everyone memorizes it...
愛されるような楽曲になってくれたら嬉しいなって思っています！
and enjoys it as a beloved song. That would make me so happy!
また、後日ライブ配信で新曲『モノポリー』だったり、今回のライブに触れた後日談など語ったり...
Also, I'll be doing a live stream later to talk about the new song "Monopoly" and behind-the-scenes stories of this live show...
一緒に見たりなどしたいなと思っているので、ぜひ！
and watch it together with you, so please...
チャンネル登録、高評価ぽち、通知もオン！
subscribe to my channel, hit the like button, and turn on notifications!
するの忘れてた人は今ぽちっとしてね！
If you forgot, please click them right now!
絶対絶対また会いに来てね！
Be sure to come see me again!
それでは...
And now...
運命は時に残酷。
Destiny is cruel at times.
あなたが選びたくて選んだものではないかもしれない。
It may not be what you wanted to choose.
だけど、いつでもあなたの人生はあなたのもの。
But your life is always your own.
人生は一度きり。
You only live once.
やり直しのきかないこのゲーム、
In this game where there are no do-overs,
あなたはどう楽しむ？
how will you enjoy it?
START
END